<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>theOmegabit</title>
        <description>Tech, dev, security, and photography.</description>
        <link>http://theomegabit.io/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://theomegabit.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 20:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 20:33:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Review: Google Pixel 2 XL</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As we rocket towards the holiday season, a lot of you out there already have a phone of choice that you’ve committed to for at least the next 6-24 months. That said, with all of the deals around various shopping “sub-holidays”, there’s an opportunity to be had, and an increasing desire to wait until this time to pick up a new device. Your’e at least safe in a sense - this is the end of both the calendar year and the phone manufacturers’ release schedules. The next big device to look forward to won’t come until early spring by way of Samsung and the Galaxy S line. That said, there’s beens one rumor that Samsung will push their next-gen release announcement to CES (we’ll see).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today however, we’re concerned with one and only one phone, the Google Pixel 2 XL. To say it’s been a bumpy ride would be an understatement. Google and the manufacturer (LG) have had a lot to take in in regards to feedback, more often than not critical and negative. But before we get into the weeds on all that fun stuff, let’s talk about what’s good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of hardware, the Pixel 2 XL is indeed a flagship phone. While many would argue Google simply slapped a higher price tag on the Pixel series vs. the more frugal Nexus line it replaced (I’d still argue this at times), Google did make some good efforts to get their in-house hardware up to snuff with competing flagships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screen is large, bright, and in the 1440p range. The finger print reader on the back is one of the best on the market. The internal CPU/RAM/Storage are all fast and spacious. And finally, the camera is, despite lacking a second lens like many other flagships at this point, somehow neck-and-neck with those same flagships. This last point is a testament to Google’s aggressive and talented software chops. There is also of course some of the other minor but important things to highlight like USB type C, water and dust resistance, and more premium build quality. On paper, the Pixel XL 2 is a fantastic phone, albeit expensive.
We’re to the point now in phones that outside of a few key things that are arguably minor all things considered, there’s not much to talk about anymore, at least on the positive side. Like I said above, if you want to drop $700+ on a phone, you’ve got a good assortment of options. Depending on your needs/wants, any of those will be a suitable companion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;full-width caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/pixel-2-xl-burn-in.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Burn in on Pixel 2 XL&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Burn in on Pixel 2 XL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;Burn in on Pixel 2 XL&quot;&gt;MS Power User&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps increasingly more beneficial is to look at what do all of these phones do poorly or at the very least, what are the cons against them. For Google this time around there were plenty. For a $700+ phone you’d be surprised how many small issues have popped up, a lot of them revolving around the display. Burn-in/ghosting/image retention, physical key issues, unresponsive touch screen edges, speaker issues, and more have plagued the device in some capacity since release. Make no mistake, while Google wants to give you the impression they spared no expense in making this premium phone, there appears to be a shit show in the QA department. More-to the first point regarding screens though, people that have followed phones and more-so tech for a while know that Google’s screen supplier of choice (LG) has a long history of hit or miss quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2012 Apple released the (at that time) first-gen Retina MacBook Pros. The screens looked great. Well, they all did until the LG supplied panels started shitting the bed after 6-12 months with noticeable and generally terrible to simply atrocious ghosting and image retention issues. Samsung’s displays meanwhile were fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Mobile phone displays are not the same as larger laptop displays for a number of reasons. But even if we cut that example out, LG themselves have had numerous issues with their own phones over the years both in hardware and software issues. (Nexus 5X, LG G4, LG G(insert anything here) boot loop anyone?) The point I’m trying to make is, while Google certainly can deserve some flack for cutting corners, and to a point, choosing to do business with LG in this scope and at this scale given their less than stellar track record, it’s really LG who has ultimately dropped the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it seems awful, right? Well. As long as you get a good phone (which is admittedly the majority), it’s a pretty good experience. It’s stock Android. Updates are nearly instant and there isn’t any bloatware to speak of. It performs on par or better than other flagship depending on the metric you’re referring to. But is it worth the cost of admission given 1) other flagships matching or exceeding many aspects of the pixel at the same price (and even less —&amp;gt; OnePlus)? That part you’ll have to answer. But in my opinion, if you are seeking something more closely related to the “iPhone of Android”, the Pixel XL 2 is where it’s at. Despite some of the issues highlighted above, it’s a good phone, performs well, and provides a great Google Experience.
 
 
&lt;em&gt;Thank you to Verizon and Kyle Communications for the review unit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://theomegabit.io/2017/12/19/pixel2-xl/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theomegabit.io/2017/12/19/pixel2-xl/</guid>
                
                <category>review</category>
                
                <category>lg</category>
                
                <category>google</category>
                
                <category>pixel2xl</category>
                
                <category>android</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Review: LG V30</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, LG has long been a manufacturer of sleeper hits. That is, their phones end up being quite good compared to the competition without any of the big media attention that the larger players get. In 2017, it’s much of the same story – Samsung, Google, OnePlus and some of the quickly growing Chinese manufacturers are overshadowing LG’s latest and greatest. Now, LG isn’t the complete victim here. They have a history of at times questionable QA, excessive model count that muddies the waters, and occasional lackluster support on the software side of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting all that aside though, in actuality the V30 is indeed a great phone. Let’s dive a bit deeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest things to focus on with the V30 is the new OLED display. LG has long had a reputation for fantastic LCD displays. But a couple years ago, Samsung made it visibly clear that OLED was the way of the future. For a variety of reasons, OLED is simply the better choice moving forward. In that regard, LG is a late bloomer. Worried about “1st gen” roughness? So far, don’t be. While LG did start fooling around with OLED with their  (plastic) POLED displays in the curved displays of the Flex and Flex 2. for the V30, the curves are gone. In it’s place is a capable  6-inch 18:9 OLED running at 1440 x 2880. Is it as good as Samsung’s? I still think Samsung’s is a tad better in the brightness arena but for all intents and purposes, it’s very close and certainly acceptable. It’s glad to see LG finally making the move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other highly controversial talking point is the rear mounted fingerprint reader and power button. LG has favored this design but that hasn’t made it any more loved or less hated. In reality it’s quite divisive. You either hate it or love it. I happen to fall in the camp that loves it. Combined with the double tap to wake feature, there’s no need to actually hit the power button. Add to that either facial recognition, pin code, or trusted devices and the restrictions that a rear mounted fingerprint reader bring are reduced significantly. Performance wise, it’s still one of the best. I’d put the LG fingerprint sensors above Samsung’s all day, any day. They’re easier to hit, have more area to hit, and are lightning quick. Hopefully Samsung will fix their not-so-nicely-placed fingerprint sensor by putting it somewhere else other than right next to the camera lenses — something you never want to put your fingers on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrapping up the external pieces of the V30 we have an all glass design similar to the last few generations of Galaxy devices, type C port for charging, single, down-firing external speaker, water and dust resistence (IP68), and Qi wireless charging. Moving inside you’re looking at, the now “standard” 8-core Qualcomm MSM8998 Snapdragon 835 with Adreno 540 GPU, 4 GB of RAM, 64 or 128 GB (V30+) of storage, 16 + 13 megapixel rear facing cameras + 5 megapixel front facing camera. The cameras in particular are one small differentiator. Where most manufacturers are going with a 2x lens for their secondary rear facing camera, LG is bucking the trend and going with a 120 degree wide angle lens. Unfortunately, the wide angle lens does not have OIS like it’s next door neighbor. Battery size is adequate at 3300 mAh in size coupled with Quickcharge 3.0. LG claims a 50% charge in 36 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest feature to talk about regarding the LG V30 is going to be the least used feature – the higher end audio. Now I’m completely in support of LG’s initiative to bring higher quality audio to the mobile world. No one really pays attention to it anymore. That said, it’s niche. And physical ports such as the headphone jack are a dying breed. In a few more years few phones will have it and this initiative will result in not much of anything for LG in terms of marketshare. Still, with a B&amp;amp;O certified quad-DAC on board, audio quality is hands down better than most all phones on the market. It’s a bittersweet pill to swallow because I personally love music and appreciate attention to audio quality. But I’m also a realist. LG is not winning any wars with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, LG took a string of almost there but ultimately short of the finish line devices and culminated in the V30. While the naming is less than impressive, the specs and actual performance are top notch for a phone of this category. The hardware is great, albeit with some design decisions that will make or break it for some, and the software is relatively clean in terms of theming goes. If you’re the type of person looking for a flagship Android device and specifically don’t want a Galaxy device, the LG V30 is one of the first alternatives you should look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you to Kyle Communications and Verizon for the review unit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://theomegabit.io/2017/11/07/lgv30/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theomegabit.io/2017/11/07/lgv30/</guid>
                
                <category>review</category>
                
                <category>lg</category>
                
                <category>v30</category>
                
                <category>android</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Review: Galaxy Note 8 Review</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Credit:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;cnet.com&quot;&gt;CNet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a number of years now, the Galaxy Note 8 has been the formidable foe of the smartphone world. For those who like everything to be bigger, faster, and top of the charts, Samsung’s Note brand has striven to cater just that. And then there was a setback, possibly major one could say. Last year Samsung had not one, but two recalls on the Note 7 because it had a higher than normal problem with… exploding. Without beating a dead horse (because it’s definitely long been beaten), let’s just say that &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; problem shouldn’t happen again. Samsung has presumably learned their lesson at least with the specific issue that led to last year’s great recall of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 2017 however, the Note 8 is the king to beat for the likes of Google, HTC, LG, et. all. But there’s only so many ways you can create a black rectangle, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we take a look at the specs, on paper, it appears to be right at the top of the Android market. The octo-core processor (4 + 4), 6 GB of RAM, and 6.3″ QHD screen are some of the chief bragging points. Bolstering the pillars of the Note 8’s feature set are things like an Adreno 540 GPU, dual 12 megapixel cameras on the rear plus an 8 megapixel shooter on the front, Iris/face/fingerprint biometrics, and more. Needless to say, we’ve really gotten to the point now where paper specs are less and less meaningful. The worst software can bring the best hardware to its knees – which is something Samsung has long been accused of doing. The Note 8, however, is beginning an upward trend towards improvement I might add.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I’ve only had the device about a week and a half, so there is time for that dreaded 6-month “Samsung bloat” to bring the performance down a notch or two. But so far, it seems better than say, Note 5 and earlier devices. Performance improvements are completely separate though to gripes with their Touch Wiz UI at its core. For that, you either accept it or hate it. (Does anyone really love it?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the software side, the biggest thing to talk about (or not) is Bixby. Bixby is Samsung’s “me too” smart assistant. And let’s just be blunt about it – it’s at best terrible. Not only is Bixby a giant waste of time for Samsung, especially since they’re coming from so far behind and just about anyone would rather have real teams of AI experts working on their AI assistant, you can’t even control this intrusion on your device. Samsung makes Bixby almost impossible to hide completely. What’s worse, an entire physical button is dedicated to Bixby that also cannot be reprogrammed for any other app or function. Talk about useless and clueless. For every small step Samsung may take forward, they do something completely stupid and idiotic such as this. Gripes aside, Bixby really isn’t that unique outside of a few unique instances when Bixby workflows come into play. Think of ifttt (but not as robust) for your phone at the system level, and controlled by voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong words aside, the rest of the software experience on the Note 8 is good to great. It’s fast, powerful, and despite it’s large size, surprisingly manageable even one handed. The Touch Wiz gripes of years past are mostly gone these days with UI and UX decisions generally consistent and tasteful. Sure, stock Android would be ideal but it’s close enough and not terrible. Plus, you can always slap your own theme of choice on top thanks to Samsung’s built in theming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the photographers of the bunch, you’ll be pleased to know that you’ve now officially joined the dual-camera bandwagon with two 12 megapixel lenses on the back featuring 1.7 and 2.4 apertures for your normal and “telephoto” 2x shooting. The selfie takers meanwhile have an upgraded 8 megapixel f/1.7 lens to capture all of life’s self incriminating moments. On the software side of things you’ve got the pretty standard Samsung UI slapped across a camera software you’re not doubt familiar with at this point if you’ve used any Samsung device in the last couple of years. The options are quite vast (especially if you flip it into full manual mode) and navigation of said app is pretty quick and painless thanks to swipe based navigation for the different camera modes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other nifty little differentiating feature of the Note’s dual-camera layout is that while it does have a similar bokeh creating effect like the iPhone 7 Plus, Samsung goes a tad further and actually lets you control the strength of the bokeh (read: background blur effect) after the fact. With Apple you get whatever you get – small but potentially super helpful. That said, while the bokeh effect was generally good to great, I did notice the Note 8 having a bit more difficulty more often than my iPhone 7 Plus in focusing on the right thing – nothing a software update can’t fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, photo quality is very good. While current mobile camera aficionados, DxO mark have not posted their Note 8 camera impressions, I’d wager the Note 8 would be at the top of the list – maybe not class leading but definitely keeping up. Colors are generally good though tend to skew a tad saturated. Also, in HDR type situations where there’s a lot of contrast between the darkest and lightest areas of the image, you’ll find the Note 8 struggling a bit keeping the bright areas from getting completely blown out if the focus is on the darker areas. Not a unique problem mind you but it is something that the latest iPhone 8 and 8 Plus handle quite well. Simply put, if you’re looking for a good mobile camera, the Note 8 won’t disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those looking for a more in-depth foray into the Note 8’s photo and video chops, I will redirect you to DxO Mark’s recently published review. TL;DR – they rank it at the same level as the new iPhone 8 Plus – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dxomark.com/samsung-galaxy-note-8-best-smartphone-zoom/&quot;&gt;DxO Mark Galaxy Note 8 Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gigantic elephant in the room that everyone is really interested about however is will it explode? I mean, we all know that in the end, Samsung bit off a bit more than they could chew in terms of pushing phone HW design to its limits so much so that it impacted battery functionality quite negatively. For the Note 8 Samsung has both designed a bit more room for the battery inside the case so that it can expand safely as well as downsized it from 3500 mAh to 3300 mAh. No self-respecting power user ever likes to see their batteries made smaller. In this case though it seems to have a negligible effect on run time (explosive tendencies still up in the air). Most days I’m taking the phone off the charger between 7-8am and then using it throughout the day to check social media (twitter/instagram/facebook) as well as constantly remaining paired to a 2nd-gen Moto 360 and AirDroid on a Mac laptop and I’m looking at 65-75% by the time I leave work at 5:30pm. Battery shrinkage withstanding, even in a normal context the Note 8’s battery is solid for an Android device as packed as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as awesome as the Note 8 seems to be in retaining it’s “King of the smartphones” crown, should you actually get it. Here’s the thing. The Note 8 is one of a few things to people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too Expensive ($900+ at it’s cheapest point)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too big (6.3″ screen is no Palm Pre)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too similar to S8 (It’s a big S8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I was coming from an iPhone 7 and 7 Plus and haven’t had an Android daily driver in at least a year. The price stung a bit, sure. The size is a tad larger than I would prefer. And I didn’t have an S8. So I ordered my own even (Shout out to Verizon for hooking me up with this review unit.) Rational thought, right? If you’re a current Note 5/S7/S8 user there’s really not too much reason to upgrade (more-so for the S7/8 users). It’s really just a larger version of those devices with a second rear facing camera. Some would disagree, citing the S-Pen and all it’s perks for what it’s worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The king is still the king, but less assuredly. LG’s V30, Google’s Pixel 2, and of course the iPhone X are just a few of the flagship contenders worthy of your attention going into the holiday season this year. Look for my LG V30 impressions in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.verizonwireless.com/smartphones/samsung-galaxy-note-8/&quot;&gt;Galaxy Note 8 on Verizon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://theomegabit.io/2017/10/02/GalaxyNote8/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theomegabit.io/2017/10/02/GalaxyNote8/</guid>
                
                <category>review</category>
                
                <category>samsung</category>
                
                <category>galaxynote</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Review: Ubiquiti Unifi</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a multitude of wireless routers, hubs, and switches aimed at the consumer market. And while the higher end may have enough features to please even more picky power users and “techies”, there’s something to be said about choices, particularly prosumer choices. One such company that falls under that category is Ubiquiti. They’ve been around for awhile to be fair. But, over time they’re continued to build upon the previous generation’s successes and keep moving forward. The team over at Ubiquiti was nice enough to send over a nice assortment of goodies including their Gateway/firewall, 8 port switch, Cloud Controller key, and an AC Pro access point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been using the gear for the last ~6 weeks and have a fairly good assortment of thoughts. And there are a lot of them…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware is still important in 2016. But more often than not, hardware lifespans can be extended with good hardware. Not to mention, poor software can shorten hardware’s lifespans. In the case of Ubiquiti, they make some pretty nice software both in terms of functionality and features as well as UI. In fact, the UI is one of my favorite aspects of it. The way it lays out data from end to end is nice, clean and generally simple without being dumbed down. That said, to make the most of the software and monitoring, you really need Ubiquiti device at every step of the way. Without a link in the chain, while nice, it just isn’t as full featured and “pretty” to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up the Ubiquiti hardware devices and cloud controller for the first time can be a bit frustrating. And this is perhaps the greatest hurdle Ubiquiti would have to address if they wanted to push down into more “normal” consumer spaces. Specifically, I already had a single AC Pro setup with the cloud controller software setup on a mac mini on my network. In the process of setting up the environment with the hardware based cloud controller key from Ubiquiti, I had an incredibly tough time getting the original AP I had to disassociate with the original controller. In theory it’s not supposed to be hard at all. But in my experience it just wouldn’t let the past go. I eventually got so frustrated with it I walked away and came back a few hours later and voila… it was ready to join the new cloud controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;full-width caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/unifidashboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unifi Dashboard&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Unifi Dashboard&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that slight aggravation was settled things got a lot easier and what one would expect. While items within the various pages and menus aren’t the most detailed out there, they’re good enough for the prosumer space in my opinion. Along the same lines, it can be a bit confusing at first to have to jump between selecting each hardware device to see configuration settings for each piece of hardware as they aren’t configurable globally in a single place. Meanwhile, other settings &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be configured in a more global menu. Needless to say, while it’s certainly easier than setting up some Cisco gear via command line, it’s not quite to the level of your typical router you’d buy at Best Buy. Really, I’d say it’s on par with Meraki in terms of layout with some minor differences between the two in what is placed where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cons aside, the software will do a ton. Everything from mutli-VLANing your networks to point-to-point VPNs (which is rather easy to setup) makes the Ubiquiti environment incredibly versatile and something that nerds will enjoy tinkering with. And of course, my favorite part is the interface that will detail a lot of different metrics about what is currently going on within your network including everything between connected devices to bandwidth. For chart junkies the Ubiquiti ecosystem’s interface is something worth exploring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, one area I wish Ubiquiti would improve on is the cloud management. For starters, the reliance on local software running on a computer or the dedicated hardware “key” seems like a weird crutch. I’d like to see it moved all to the cloud like Meraki’s solution. It’s simply one less complication to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’d rate the software more than acceptable. While it can take a bit of learning and getting used to (especially if you’re moving from consumer to prosumer),  it is slightly more approachable than Cisco/Meraki on both price and learning curve standpoints. And to recap, I like charts… and colors. And when you have end-to-end components that all talk nicely together, it makes for a pretty great experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;AC Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;full-width caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/unifi-acpro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unifi AC Pro&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Unifi AC Pro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 x Dual-band antennas, 2.4 GHz: 3 dBi, 5 GHz: 6 dBi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;802.11a/b/g/n/ac w/ band steering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;weather resistant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Passive Power over Ethernet (48 V), 802.3af/803.2at Supported&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Supported Voltage Range: 44 to 57 VDC)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Max power consumption: 9 W&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supported speeds:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;802.11a&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6, 9, 12, 18, 24, 36, 48, 54 Mb/s802.11n&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6.5 to 450 Mb/s (MCS0 – MCS23, HT 20/40)802.11ac&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6.5 to 1300 Mb/s (MCS0 – MCS9 NSS1/2/3, VHT 20/40/80)802.11b&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1, 2, 5.5, 11 Mb/s802.11g&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6, 9, 12, 18, 24, 36, 48, 54 Mb/s&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AC Pros are perhaps one of the nicest looking yet simple APs we’ve come across. The white disk with center glowing circle seems very Apple-like in simplicity. The glowing circle pulls double duty, too, as an indicator of the APs status between no connected clients, connected clients, errors/issues, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the underside are just a few ports – a power port, an ethernet port and a secondary ethernet port to daisy chain APs together. Being that the AC Pros support standard PoE (power over ethernet) — and not that 24v passive junk which is annoying — you’re best option to reduce clutter and unnecessary wires is make sure you have a switch that also supports PoE. The 8 port switch by Ubiquiti just happens to have said support, though any PoE switch will work. You can sit the AC Pro flat as well as mount it on a wall or ceiling with the provided mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other nice perk: the AC Pros are weather resistant enough that you can legit mount them outside without any special covering or case. So, for those of you looking to extend your network to a detached building or simply cover the backyard in modern wireless goodness, the barrier to doing that is much lower. All you need is some Cat 5 cable run to the location of the AP and said AP. The software will then step in and give you an easy way to add and extend to your network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months I’ve had a solid experience. There has been a single instance in which the AP needed a reboot but other than that, coverage has been great, speeds high, and the experience very much “set it and forget it” after the initial grief. I will admit I was skeptical at first regarding range with the AC Pro vs. some of the other routers I have which feature much larger, external antennas. Generally speaking, the larger the antenna the better range you’ll get. Now, I’m not a hardware engineer so I’m not going to pretend I know exactly how or why something with smaller internal antennas on this prosumer device can match (and at times exceed) the ranage of something, say, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/2015/01/05/d-link-wifi-routers-powerline/&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;. Just know that the AC Pro can. It needs to be said though, wireless is a fickle thing and your experience could (and very likely will) vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Unifi AC Mesh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;alignright caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/unifimesh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unifi AC Mesh points&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Unifi AC Mesh points&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, these mesh points from Ubiquiti are actually much newer than the other gear in the review here. But over time as I’ve continued using the Unifi gear, it’s been a welcome addition to further bolster network coverage and versatility with the two additional mesh points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way the work is much like any other repeater. The dual-band AC units can be both wired and wireless added to your network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in wireless mode, I didn’t see any noticeable differences in speed or performance when several devices were connected to both the mesh point and the downstream wireless uplink AP. In a real world, high speed test however, the performance degradation when multiple hops are involved cannot be forgotten or discounted. In the scope of a normal sized house, it’s not something you’ll likely have to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Switch &amp;amp; Firewall/Gateway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switch hardware these days is honestly kind of boring. It’s the software features that make the HW intriguing and differentiate one device from the next. As we touched on earlier, Ubiquiti’s software is quite nice to look at and only gets better the more Ubiquiti devices you have running together. And that is the big kicker here – to truly get the best experience you really need to have as much Ubiquiti hardware as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the switch and gateway one is able to literally control just about anything, and all via a wonderful GUI that brings networking into the modern world so you can get in, do what you need, and get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spec wise the switch and gateway are what you would expect – multiple 1 gig ports all providing standard PoE for any other PoE devices you might want to plug into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(8) Gigabit RJ45 Ports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(2) SFP Ports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-Blocking Throughput: 10 Gbps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Switching Capacity: 20 Gbps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forwarding Rate: 14.88 Mpps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maximum Power Consumption: 150W&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supports POE+ IEEE 802.3at/af and 24V Passive PoE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quiet, Fanless Operation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rackmountable with Rack-Mount Brackets (Included)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desktop-Mountable(DonotphysicallystacktheUS-8-150W.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much the same as the switch, the gateway is a great addition to any network as it is a more business-y security gateway. That is, it actively works toward protecting your network to intrusions from the outside. Some of the more notable specs include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(3) 10/100/1000 RJ45 Ports*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(1) RJ45 Serial Console Port&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quiet, Fanless Operation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wall?Mounting Capability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Layer 3 Forwarding Performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Heat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most of the discussion’s we’ve had with others regarding Ubiquiti hardware has been almost unanimously positive we have had people chat with us regarding component quality. While I can’t speak for the quality of the components (outside my expertise) I will say that I never had any issues with the units Ubiquiti sent. To be fair, ~4 months isn’t a great length in the true “long term review” spectrum. Nonetheless, the ambient temperature in the building I have been in was quite warm (~80-87) during the middle of summer. Yes, the Ubiquiti hardware has been running hot, maybe even “wow, that’s hot for a gadget” (specifically, the gateway got the hottest). But they haven’t so much as blinked in the higher operating temps they’ve been subjected to. And for that I can at least say I’m appreciative. Perhaps in 12 months we’ll see how things are still fairing. Maybe they’ll throw up a white flag in 18 months. For now, though, all I can say is that I have not had any issues with them. I’m pleased with how the hardware has performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Wrap-up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;alignright caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ubiquiticlose.png&quot; alt=&quot;Unifi&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Unifi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of people are going to spring for something cheap from Best Buy. And that’s fine. Most people don’t want or need the features that Ubiquiti or any other pro-sumer/business level hardware and software provides. But for those who do, Ubiquiti is a great option to consider compared to one of the other big names in this space – Meraki (by Cisco). While Meraki is a more fleshed out and truly enterprise level product, it also 1) costs more and 2) can be more involved, especially if you delve into the more traditional Cisco namespace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say most anyone considering this setup almost certainly can figure out some of the software gripes I had early on. It was annoying but not a show stopper. That said, it also highlighted another area that Cisco (and frankly, many other consumer level hardware) has an advantage over – community and support. The community around Ubiquiti is very vocal and loyal, but it’s also small. There’s no way around it – the community is simply small, which makes finding answers to questions a little more involved and time consuming. Add to that the lack of deeper documentation into the hardware/software and you have the recipe for a headache when problems pop up, especially if you’re not the type of person who is ok with rolling up their sleeves and getting their hands dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial setup and HW quality concerns aside, my time with the various pieces of hardware has been largely non-eventful. And really, that’s what you want. Set it and forget it. When you need to change something, get in, change it and get out while also being able to get a good look at your network when you want to dig deeper thanks to the great reporting and charting of various metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to get into the pro-sumer space for your home or even small business, Ubiquiti is worth a look. The lower cost of entry to other options means it’s approachable and a much lower risk if it ends up not being a right fit down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;A big thank you to Ubiquiti who was kind enough to send all this gear over.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://theomegabit.io/2017/08/25/ubiquiti-unifi/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theomegabit.io/2017/08/25/ubiquiti-unifi/</guid>
                
                <category>review</category>
                
                <category>wireless</category>
                
                <category>networking</category>
                
                <category>ubiquiti</category>
                
                <category>unfi</category>
                
                <category>accesspoint</category>
                
                <category>wifi</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>